Shaikh M. Shariq

Karāchi, Sindh, Pakistan



shaikhshariq039@gmail.com



+923362081561



linkedin.com/in/alshaikhshariq

Summary

Experienced Information Technology professional graduated from Iqra University and Currently enrolled in MSCS program from NED University Karachi Pakistan. With demonstrated history of working in he information technology and services industry. Java, Spring, PHP, Laravel, HTML/CSS JavaScript/AJAX, Cordova, Ionic, Azure, MySQL, NoSQL.

Experience



Senior Back End Developer

Solar Informatics

Jan 2023 - Present (5 months)

- Working on RESTful Web-Services for SAAS application with Spring Boot, Java
- Leading and maintaining Batch Job Engine. Includes, SpringBatch, ScheduledFuture, TaskScheduler, ETL Batch Processing.
- Working on stand alone Batch Scheduler using (Spring cloud, spring batch, azure spring apps)
- Working with Azure Spring Apps for DS architecture (Spring Cloud Microservices and NoSQL)
- Proficient understanding of VCS, Bitbucket, Git Bash, Azure CLI.
- Agile Tools: Jira and Microsoft Teams

Back End Developer

Solar Informatics

Oct 2020 - Dec 2022 (2 years 3 months)

- Working on RESTful Web-Services for SAAS application with Spring Boot, Java
- Leading Batch Job Engine. Includes, SpringBatch, ScheduledFuture, TaskScheduler, ETL Batch Processing.
- Integrations in backend like, JasperReports, SendGrid, PowerBi, using AAD (Azure Active Directory)
- Working on Documentation Hierarchy using Azure Blob Storage and file conversion in spring web services.
- Working with Azure Spring Apps for DS architecture (Spring Cloud Microservices and NoSQL)
- Maintaining CI/CD pipelines for Azure Spring Apps
- Alongside deployment on Heroku and Azure
- Proficient understanding of VCS, Bitbucket, Git Bash, Azure CLI.
- Agile Tools: Jira and Microsoft Teams

Back End Web Developer

FM Software Solutions Pvt, Ltd.

Mar 2020 - Sep 2020 (7 months)

- Building new web-based application artitechture (PHP/Laravel).
- Develop and design a custom ERP Modules.

- Writing feature specification and documentation as needed.

Mobile App Developer

Nash Technologies

Jan 2020 - Jun 2020 (6 months)

- Working on hybrid app development environment (Cordova/PhoneGap, Ionic5).
- Mobile application's listing, JSON parsing and web service (Core PHP, AJAX).
- Proficient understanding of code versioning tools, such as Git.

Web Developer

CentoSquare

Sep 2019 - Feb 2020 (6 months)

- Build new and maintain existing web-based applications.
- Develop, design, implement and test high-quality feature
- Implementations for an enterprise application.
- Writing feature specification and documentation as needed.

Android Developer

CentoSquare

May 2019 - Feb 2020 (10 months)

Maintaining web panel for android application. Working with rest APIs.

Working with teams on code using GitHub.

Field Operations Supervisor

Leisure Leagues PK

Aug 2018 - Jan 2020 (1 year 6 months)

Scheduling matches pitch and ground support. Updating score sheet on Web-App

🔅 IT Support Technician & Network Administrator

Media Monitors Pakistan

Jul 2018 - Aug 2018 (2 months)

System support along with software QA.

Installation, maintenance, repairing and recovery.

Monitoring and analyzing systems.

Education



NED University of Engineering and Technology

Master's degree, Data Engineering & Information Management May 2021 - Present

III Igra University (Official)

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science 2014 - 2019

Skills

Java Development • Coding Practices • Jasper • Spring Boot • Spring Cloud • Microsoft Azure • Microservices • Spring Batch • Extract, Transform, Load (ETL) • Azure Active Directory